# DATA CLEANING | DATA ANALYTICS | DATA SCIENCE PROTOTYPING

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

**Data Management:** Predictive analytics, database design and management, data quality assessment, pattern identification, visualization of data insights, skilled at data process automation, DevOps, data documentation and analysis

**Research:** Data science research methods, data mining, SQL database migration/planning, data analysis with Python – prototyping/tool building; 6 years' experience Markov Hidden Method and Monte Carlo for risk analysis/efficient frontier

**Communication/Team Skills/Professional Practice:** Highly developed interpersonal/communication skills; Proven team collaboration and independent productivity; Critical thinking and attention to detail

#### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

**Bachelor of Applied Science Data Analytics**, Bellevue College, Bellevue WA

GPA 3.167

Expected 2022

- Studies focus on analytics of Natural Language Processing and artificially intelligent solutions for automation
- Coursework: Data Visualizations (Extract SQL/Excel to create Tableau dashboards), Database Analytics (Microsoft SQL server, Tableau, Python), Introduction to Analytics (Statistical analysis of a MySQL database in R)

AWS Certified Architect Cloud Practitioner, online

in progress

AWS DataCamp, online

2019

## **RELATED EXPERIENCE**

Data Analyst (contract) - Lifespan Bioscience, Seattle, WA

Sept 2017 - Mar 2018

- Unified DevOps team of 4 code namespace, implemented version control and VM clouds
- Lead Machine Learning team to sort and classify gene expressions with Monte Carlo and KNN
- SQL data sanitation: found, cleaned, organized and prepared clean data from 27 countries
- Connected data tooling for Elisakit, Protein, BioChemical, Mono & Polyclonal antibody research

Data Analyst - Your Data Talking, Seattle, WA

Oct 2014 - Mar 2019

- Created and cleaned MySQL, Postgres, and SQLite, conduct EDA, HR analytics and communicate with stakeholders
- Consultatively trained Salesforce and Zoho CRM users on best practices to drive growth
- Merged existing or create new databases API's, customized sales process software
- Data cleansing and clustering for archival via APACHE analytics backend system

Salesforce Admin/Developer (remote) – Presbyterian Senior Services, New York, NY

2015 to March 2017

- Migrated MySQL and Access data into Salesforce, biweekly software releases
- Full cycle developer in charge of process research and 24/7 on-call security admin

Data Analyst (remote) - SPROXIL, Boston, MA

Sept 2015 to June 2016

- Led analysis of social media and website data focus on marketing to recurring customers
- Google Analytics subject matter expert, visualize customer traffic, monetize opportunities
- Analysis of 160 gigabyte SQL data lake, startup pharma market, produce ad hoc reports

Financial Advisor - Country Financial – Bellevue, WA

Oct 2007 - May 2014

- Provided hoc data regression and CRM pipeline analysis for Monte Carlo Risk assessment
- Grew sales from \$340k to \$840k, annual analysis of \$2MM AUM in 482 clients' accounts
- Analyzed B2B and B2C portfolios for risk management with Hidden Markov Chain analysis

### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Archive Assistant (intern), Secretary of State – Washington State Historical Archives, Seattle, WA Sept 2019 – June 2020

- Assisted archivists with document research and retrieval
- Devised research method using computer vision/NLP to automate scanning of documents for automated retrieval/analysis

Mentor (Volunteer), Python Software Foundation – Seattle PuPPy, Galvanize, Seattle, WA

March 2015 - Nov 2018

· Work in small groups with adults bi-weekly on Python programming and data science education